Ankit Singh Kushwah

C++ Game Programmer

HORSHAM,UK

I am a passionate software engineer with 5 years of experience in the games industry. I am looking for opportunities where the team is pushing technical boundaries, creating fresh gameplay experiences and where I get to tackle problems which really challenge me to push my technical & creative knowledge. I want to make games fun.

EXPERIENCE:

C++ Gameplay Programmer | Unannounced AAA Game | CREATIVE ASSEMBLY | UK

2022 - Present

- Implemented reinforcement system & different spawners
- Implemented various ability behaviours
- Implemented stats/attribute modification system & tag system
- Implemented movement orders/behaviours : Jumping, Tactical Retreating & Teleportation
- Implemented damage rules for array of different interactions : Melee, Range, AoE etc
- Created proposals & Refactored systems
- Implemented various features in C# and exposed C++ systems to C# for designers
- Added UI code support for various features
- Added Input actions with modifiers & triggers for various features
- Wrote plugins for Jetbrains rider for code analysis & quick fixes for inhouse libraries usage

Game Programmer | GAMEZOP | INDIA

2021 - 2022

- Developed Pool Master: A 8 ball pool multiplayer game
- Developed Street Dunkies: A roly-poly physics based basket ball game
- Collaborated on various casual titles

Game Programmer on Contract | XANSR TECHNOLOGIES | INDIA

4 Months - 2020

• Ported Temple Run 2 to HTML 5 for Imangi Studios for Poki dot com

Software Engineer Intern | EA | INDIA

2018 - 2019

- Implemented Spin board for Bejeweled Blitz
- Added sprite sheet animation to in-house engine
- Updated SDKs for telemetry & Ads
- Did a knowledge sharing session on SIMD
- Bug fixes for different mobile devices
- · Peer code reviews

CONTACT:

Email: ankitsinghkushwah@outlook.com

Linkedin: https://linkedin.com/in/

videogamechef

PORTFOLIO/TECH DEMOS:

ankitsinghkushwah.github.io

EDUCATION:

Backstage Pass Institute of Gaming and Technology

Bachelors in Computer Science & Game Development 2015-2019

PUBLISHED ARTICLES:

Skeletal Animation with OpenGL

LearnOpenGL dot com | 2020

SKILLS:

Languages: C/C++, C#, Python & Typescript

Graphics APIs: OpenGL & DirectX Game Engine: Unreal 5 & Godot

VCS: Git & Perforce

Performance Analysis: RenderDoc &

Superluminal

SHIPPED GAMES:

Temple Run 2 (>50M plays)
Pool Master (5.5M plays)
Street Dunkies (500k plays)
Bejeweled Blitz (10M Downloads)

PERSONAL PROJECTS HIGHLIGHTS:

Eklavya Engine: C++ game engine with custom rigid body physics, skeletal animation & OpenGL Renderer

CPU Based real time Ray Tracer